Okay, welcome, we're going to talk about playing the Blues,
好的，欢迎，我们要讨论弹奏布鲁斯，
musically, the Blues is a couple of different things,
从音乐上讲，布鲁斯是一些不同的东西，
it involves single notes,
它涉及到单音符，
we're going to add some notes to the major scale,
我们将在大调音阶上添加一些音符，
some notes we're going to delete,
删除一些音符，
some notes we're just going to adjust,
调整一些音符，
and it also involves chords
它还涉及和弦，
of a very specific chord progression,
一个特殊的和弦进程，
that's twelve measures long called the Blues chord progression,
也就是 12 小节长，称为布鲁斯和弦进程，
twelve bar Blues, you may have heard of that.
12 小节布鲁斯，你可能听过。
First thing we're talking about are the Blues notes,
我们首先讨论的是布鲁斯音符，
what are the Blues notes,
什么是布鲁斯音符，
let's talk about that first,
让我们先来谈谈，
the Blues notes are the flatted third, the flatted fifth and the flatted seventh of the major scale,
布鲁斯音符是降三、降五、降七的大调音阶，
the blues scale is taken, is derived from that major scale,
布鲁斯音阶是从大调音阶衍生出来的，
so if you look at your major scale,
所以如果你看大调音阶，
we have one two three four five six and seven.
我们有 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 。
Now, we're just going to add and adjust a couple of those notes,
现在，我们只需添加和调整其中的几个音符，
we're going to add the flatted third,
我们添加降三，
so now the blues scale would be one two, flatted third,
所以现在布鲁斯音阶是 1 2 ，降 3 ，
you can still have the other third in there,
你仍然有另一个 3 在那里，
then we have fourth,
然后我们有 4 ，
then we squeeze in that flatted fifth,
然后我们挤进那个降 5 ，
then we have the fifth, the sixth,
然后我们有 5 和 6 ，
then we had the flatted seventh and we take out the regular seventh,
然后我们有降 7 ，我们把常规的 7 拿出去，
so in the Blues,
所以在布鲁斯中，
we never use that normal seventh, that regular seventh,
我们从来不使用常规的 7 ，
part of that is,
部分原因是，
if we do that,
如果我们这样做了，
we lose completely the whole tonality of playing the Blues,
我们就完全失去了弹奏布鲁斯的整个音调，
so that's why we have to keep that flatted seventh there.
所以这就是为什么我们必须保持降 7 。
So let's talk about two of those specific pitches first,
所以让我们来谈谈两个特定的音高，
the flatted third and the flatted seventh,
降 3 和降 7 ，
flatted seventh is probably the most critical to get that Blues sound.
降 7 可能是发出布鲁斯声音最关键的。
So if we're in the C scale, the c major scale,
所以如果我们在 C 音阶中， C 大调音阶，
one is C, two is D, E F G A B and C,
1 是 C ， 2 是 D ， E F G A B C ，
that would be the major scale,
这就是大调音阶，
now when I add those blues notes in it,
现在当我把那些布鲁斯音符加进去，
I've got C D,
我有 C D ，
I throw this Eb in there,
我把这个 Eb 放在这里，
E F and Gb G A Bb and C,
E F Gb G A Bb C ，
now that's kind of the musical,
现在这是一种音乐，
you when you're looking at a musical notation
当你在看乐谱的时候，
just to understand what the Blues notes are made up of,
为了理解布鲁斯音符是由什么组成的，
now, you don't have to have all of those notes in there,
你不需要把所有的音符都放在里面，
you don't have to completely play that what nine or ten note scale,
你不需要完全弹奏九或十个音符的音阶，
in order for it to work,
为了让它发挥作用，
each pick and choose and you can add some and delete some others,
每一次挑选和选择中，你可以添加一些和删除一些，
now I'm a guitar player,
现在我是一名吉他手，
so all guitar players,
所以所有的吉他演奏者，
we like the easy way out,
我们都喜欢这个简单的方法，
so the easiest way we can squeeze these Blues notes in
最简单的方法是我们把这些布鲁斯音符挤进去，
and I don't want to have to learn another scale,
我不想学习另一个音阶，
I want to take these scales that I already know
我想用这些我已经知道的音阶，
and be able to use them
能够使用它们，
and still get some [] out of them,
还能从中获得一些[]，
there's where some of the beauty comes in learning our pentatonic scales,
这就是学习五声音阶的一些好处，
and now we're going to use them,
现在我们要使用它们，
with the Blues progression.
使用布鲁斯进程。
Okay, so if I take a C minor pentatonic scale,
好的，所以如果我用 C 小调五声音阶，
look at those notes,
看看那些音符，
I've got a C, an Eb, an F, a G and a Bb,
我得到 C Eb F G Bb ，
well, already in that scale,
好的，在那个音阶里，
I've got almost all of the keynotes in there,
我已经得到了几乎所有的基调，
I've dropped the second, I've dropped the sixth in there,
我丢掉了 2 ，我丢掉了 6 ，
but that's okay
但是没关系，
and Blues you really don't need those too much, anyway,
布鲁斯，你真的不需要太多，
it's still good to have them in,
有它们在里面也是好的，
but an easy way to get started with it is
但是开始的一个简单的方法是，
just playing the minor pentatonic form,
你只弹奏小调五声音阶形式，
when you're doing Blues,
当你在弹布鲁斯的时候，
if we're in c let's say,
比如，如果我们是 C 调的，
I would play a C minor pentatonic form with it,
我会弹奏 C 小调五声音阶形式，
and that will make it sound bluesy,
这会让它听起来很布鲁斯，
let me show you what I'm talking about.
让我来告诉你我在说什么。
So if I'm playing a C minor pentatonic scale,
所以，如果我弹奏的是 C 小调五声音阶，
it would be up here at the what eight fret,
它应该是在第八品，
okay, just a regular C minor pentatonic
好的，只是一个常规的 C 小调五声音阶，
and take it down,
然后往下，
okay, regular first for minor pentatonic,
好的，首先是常规的小调五声音阶，
okay, now when I added to a Blues form,
现在，当我加入布鲁斯形式，
let's see what happens,
让我们看看会发生什么，
let's get our, let's get our loop going again,
让我们重新开始循环，
and I'm going to throw this C minor pentatonic,
我要弹奏这个 C 小调五声音阶，
and you can hear how it kind of fits and starts sounding bluesy.
你可以听到它是如何开始听起来布鲁斯的。
Okay, now that was basically the C minor pentatonic
好的，现在基本上是 C 五声音阶，
and I'm getting double use out of it,
我两次使用它，
I'm using it as my Blues scale as well,
我也用它作为我的布鲁斯音阶，
now it doesn't have a couple of the notes,
现在它没有几个音符，
it doesn't have that flatted fifth in it,
它没有降 5 ，
but basically that's it,
但基本上就是这样，
if I wanted to add that flatted fifth to the minor pentatonic form,
如果我想把降 5 加到小调五声音阶形式中，
I just have to squeeze that note in there.
我只需要把那个音符挤进去。
So let's take a look at that form,
让我们看看这个形式，
I've got the first pentatonic form,
我得到了第一个五声音阶形式，
we said we're going to play it,
我们说过我们要弹这个，
now let's go back and play
现在让我们回来弹奏，
and play an A minor just where where we're at,
弹奏一个 A 小调，
and I'm going to play this in A minor,
我要弹奏 A 小调，
but I'm going to squeeze that flatted fifth in there,
但我要把那个降 5 挤进去，
okay, you see if you can follow along with me,
好的，看看你能不能跟上，
here we go, first fourth,
我们开始，第一个，第四个，
first, here's that flatted fifth that's diamond note,
第一个，这是降 5 ，钻石符号的音符，
okay that's gonna be our flatted fifth note,
好的，这将是我们的降 5 音符，
keep going through it,
继续往前走，
here comes another one, on the Eb.
这里是另一个， Eb 。
Okay, so if I did that fast,
好的，如果我弹得快一点，
if I take it down,
如果我往下，
see how that flatted fifth really gives it that bluesy sound,
看到那个降 5 是如何发出布鲁斯的声音的，
one thing, on that flatted fifth, it's so,
一件事，在那个降 5 上，它很，
how shall I say,
我该怎么说呢，
it's got so much tension in that note,
它在音符上有很大的张力，
that you don't want to land on it for a very long time,
你不想在上面停留很长一段时间，
you kind of throw it in there,
你把它扔进去，
speckle it in there a little bit,
让它在那里有一点斑点，
but you don't want to land on it,
但你不想停在上面，
if I land on it,
如果我停在上面，
it's too dissonant and it doesn't work.
它太不和谐了，它不起作用了。
The flatted third works well, the flatted seventh works well,
降 3 很好，降 7 很好，
the flatted fifth is a little bit so strong,
降 5 有点太强了，
you don't want to really land on it too much,
你不想太多地使用它，
use it, but just kind of sneak into it,
使用它，但是只是偷偷地进入它，
as you're using it up and down.
因为你在上下使用它。
Okay, now that's some of the Blues notes,
好的，这是一些布鲁斯音符，
that that are derived from the major scale,
是从大调音阶派生出来的，
let's talk about the other half of it,
让我们来谈谈它的另一半，
which is the Blues chord progression.
也就是布鲁斯和弦进程。
Okay, it is 12 measures long,
好的，它有 12 小节长，
and it goes in a very specific way,
它有一种非常特别的方式，
there's many different versions of it,
它有很多不同的版本，
are ways you can derive different things from it,
你可以从它那里获得不同的东西，
here it is in its most basic form.
这它是最基本的形式。
The first four bars are the one chord,
前四个小节是一个和弦，
in any key,
在任何调中，
if I'm in C, it would be a C chord,
如果我是 C ，就是 C 和弦，
if I'm an F, would be an F chord.
如果我是 F ，就是 F 和弦。
Next, on bar five and six,
下一个，在第五小节和第六小节上，
I go to the four of whatever key I'm in,
不管我是什么调，我使用 4 ，
if I'm in C,
如果我在 C 调，
I just count up the major scale, C D E F,
我数一下大调音阶 C D E F ，
and I play the F chord for two bars.
我弹奏两个小节的 F 和弦。
Got it,
明白了吗，
so I've got the one chord for four bars,
所以我得到了四个小节的 1 和弦，
the four chord for two bars,
两个小节的 4 和弦，
and then for the next two bars, I go back to the one chord.
然后在接下来的两个小节中，我回到 1 和弦。
So, I've got four the one chord,
所以，我有四个 1 和弦，
two with the four chord,
两个 4 和弦，
then back to two with the one chord,
然后回到两个 1 和弦，
the last four bars, I use the five chord,
最后四个小节，我使用 5 和弦，
which in C, would be the G, right,
在 C 中是 G ，
C D E F G,
C D E F G ，
G is the fifth step in the scale,
G 是音阶的第五步，
so I'd use the G or the five,
所以我会用 G 或 5 ，
the next measure I'd go to four,
下一个小节，我会到 4 ，
or in C, would be an F,
或者在 C 中是 F ，
and then I go back to one for two bars.
然后我又回到两个小节的 1 和弦。
So it's twelve bars all put together,
所以十二个和弦放在一起，
let's go through it again,
让我们再来一遍，
the first, first for our one chords,
前四个是 1 和弦，
then in bar five, I have the four chords,
然后在第五小节，我有 4 和弦，
then in bar seven, I have the one chord,
然后在第七小节，我有 1 和弦，
and then I go five, four, two bars of one.
然后我有 5 4 ，两个小节的 1 和弦。
Add that all up together,
所有这些加在一起，
you get twelve bars, twelve bar Blues.
你得到十二小节布鲁斯。
Let's listen to that example one more time
让我们再听一次这个例子，
and see if you can hear those chords changing between one and four.
看看你是否能听到这些和弦在 1 到 4 之间的变化。
Okay, here we go,
好的，，我们开始，
starts on one chord and we'll do this for four measures,
从 1 和弦开始，我们弹奏四个小节，
here comes the four chord,
这里是 4 和弦，
back to the one,
回到 1 和弦，
here comes five,
这里是 5 和弦，
it comes four,
这里是 4 ，
back to one.
回到 1 。
Okay, now we're in C,
好的，现在我们在 C 中，
so I'm gonna play it in C,
所以我将以 C 开始弹奏，
starts on a C chord,
从 C 和弦开始，
F chord now,
现在是 F 和弦，
C chord,
C 和弦，
G F C.
G F C 。
So that's the Blues chord progression in C or a C Blues,
这就是 C 调的布鲁斯和弦进程或 C 布鲁斯，
now you've learned the notes, the Blues notes,
现在你已经学会了音符，布鲁斯音符，
that we can apply into our C scale
我们可以在 C 音阶中使用，
and we can also use our C minor pentatonic
我们也可以使用 C 小调五声音阶，
as an easy way to find notes,
作为一种简单的方法来找到音符。
and we've also learned the Blues chord progression,
我们还学习了布鲁斯和弦进程，
now let's take a look at some triads.
现在让我们来看看一些三和弦。
Okay, welcome to the how music works section,
好的，欢迎来到音乐原理部分，
in this section, we're going to talk about triads,
在这一部分，我们将谈论三和弦，
all the chords that we've learned so far are
我们目前所学到的和弦都是
all based off of a certain type of a connection pattern with the major scale,
基于一种特定类型的与大调音阶的连接模式，
it's called triad,
它被称为三和弦，
a triad in its most simplest form is just a combination of three notes,
一个三和弦最简单的形式是三个音符的组合，
hence the name triad.
由此得名三和弦，
Okay, now we pull these notes from the major scale,
好的，现在我们从大调音阶中拿出这些音符，
okay, you see your C major scale there,
好的，你看你的 C 大调音阶，
now the notes that we use to make chords
我们用这些音符来组成和弦，
out of those are the triad,
组成三和弦，
that were going to use for our purposes,
用来达到自己的目的，
we're going to pull and adjust the one, the three and the five,
我们拿出 1 3 5 ，
if I'm in c that would be the C, E and G.
如果我在 C 中，那就是 C E G 。
Okay, now there are four different types of triads,
好的，现在有四种不同类型的三和弦，
that you need to worry about as a guitar player,
作为吉他手，你需要考虑的，
and they've got four different names that go with them,
它们有四个不同的名字，
the major triad,
大三和弦，
its formula is built on the one, the three and the five,
它的公式是建立在 1 3 5 ，
the first, third and fifth notes pulled out of a scale, major scale,
从大调音阶中拿出第一、第三和第五音符，
so if I'm in C, it would be a C, an E and a G,
所以如果我在 C 中，它将是 C E G 。
if I'm in F, it would be an F, an A and a C,
如果我在 F ，那就是 F A C ，
the formula for a major triad, one three five.
大三和弦的公式是 1 3 5 。
Next one is minor,
下一个是小调，
a minor triad is one, flat three, five,
小三和弦是 1 b3 5 ，
I take that third and I lower it a half step,
我取第三个，然后把它降半音，
so if I'm in C, it would be C, then Eb and G,
所以如果我在 C ，它就是 C Eb G ，
if I'm at F, would be F Ab and C.
如果我在 F ，将是 F Ab C 。
Okay, the next one is augmented,
好的，下一个是增强的，
that's, that specific triads formula is one three sharp five,
具体的三和弦公式是 1 3 #5 ，
so in C, it would be C E G#,
所以在 C 中，它将是 C E G# ，
I raise that fifth up.
我把第五个音升高。
The next one is diminished,
下一个是减弱的，
and diminished, the formula is one, flat three, flat five,
减三和弦的公式是 1 b3 b5 ，
C Eb Gb.
C Eb Gb 。
So we've covered four different types,
我们讲了四种不同的三和弦，
a major triad is one three five,
大三和弦是 1 3 5 ，
a minor triad is one flat three five,
小三和弦是 1 b3 5 ，
an augmented triad is one three sharp five
增三和弦是 1 3 #5 ，
and a diminished triad is one, flat three, flat five.
减三和弦是 1 b3 b5 ，
Okay, now let's take a listen to some of these triads
好的，现在让我们来听听这些三和弦中的一些，
and see if you can hear train [] and train our ear
看看你是否能，训练我们的耳朵，
to hear the difference between major and minor and diminished and augmented.
听出大调、小调、增强和减弱之间的区别。
So if I'm in C,
所以，如果我在 C ，
C major triad would be C E and G,
C 大三和弦是 C E G ，
which would sound like this, C E G,
听起来就像这个， C E G ，
minor triad would be C Eb G,
小三和弦是 C Eb G ，
here's major, here's minor,
这是大调，这是小调，
can you hear the difference, when that third goes down,
你能听出来第三个音调下降了吗，
augmented would be C E G#,
增三和弦是 C E G# ，
okay, major and minor are the ones that we use almost all the time,
好的，大调和小调是我们几乎所有时间都在使用的，
every now and then we throw in augmented,
时不时地，我们会增加一些，
every now and then we throw in diminished,
时不时地，我们会减弱一些，
but the most significant ones you're gonna run across our majors and minors.
但最重要的是，你会遇到我们的大调和小调。
The augmented is C E G#,
增三和弦是 C E G# ，
the last one is the diminished, would be C Eb Gb,
最后一个是减三和弦，是 C Eb Gb ，
hear the difference in that,
听出它们的不同了吗，
so they go through them all,
再听一遍，
C major, C minor, C augmented, C diminished.
C 大调， C 小调， C 增强， C 减弱。
Okay, they don't sound too musical put by themselves,
好的，它们自己听起来不太有音乐性，
when you put them in a chord progression,
当你把它们放在和弦进程中时，
that's when it starts making sense.
它就开始有意义了。
Okay, here's our assignment for this session,
好的，这是我们这节课的作业，
your assignment is to practice the penta tonic forms with the Blues notes
你的作业是练习包含布鲁斯音符的五声音阶形式，
in all of the keys the full range of the instrument,
在整个乐器上的所有调中，
now I showed you the first pentatonic form back in our session,
我给你展示了第一个五声音阶形式，
but there's also, remember there's also four other forms,
但是记得还有其他四种形式，
five of them put together
其中五种形式放在一起，
with your squeezing that extra note in it,
你在里面放入额外的音符，
so get those underneath your fingers be able to play them,
所以把它们放在你的手指下能够演奏它们，
the full range of the instrument in any key.
乐器的全部在任何调上。
Next is memorize the Blues chord progression,
下一个是记住布鲁斯和弦进程，
that's probably the easiest thing,
这可能是最容易的事情，
four bars of one, two bars of four, two bars of one, a five, a four and two ones,
四小节 1 ，两小节 4 ，两小节 1 ，一小节 5 ，一小节 4 ，两小节 1 ，
that's a good thing to commit to memory,
这是一件值得记住的事情，
think about it in different keys,
用不同的音调思考，
be able to get a handle on
能够处理，
the different keys and different chords,
不同的音调和不同的和弦，
that go in those different keys through that Blues progression,
通过布鲁斯进程，
play the Blues chord progressions in the various keys from the exercises in your book,
弹奏书中练习中不同音调的布鲁斯和弦进程，
also practice soloing using the Blues pentatonic form,
也练习 solo 使用布鲁斯五声音阶形式，
over the Blues progressions in the Jam tracks,
练习在 Jam 曲目中的布鲁斯进程，
there's lots of things for you to work on,
你有很多事情要做，
lots of opportunities for you to practice and get better at it,
有很多机会让你练习，让你做得更好，
so I encourage you to keep doing that,
所以我鼓励你继续这样做，
so I'll see you next time.
所以我们下一次再见。
Okay, for our workshop time today,
好了，今天我们的 workshop 时间，
let's review a couple things,
让我们回顾几件事，
our Blues notes are the flatted third, the flatted fifth and the flatted seventh,
我们的布鲁斯音符是，降 3 ，降 5 和降 7 ，
derived from that major scale in C,
从 C 大调音阶派生出来，
the flatted third would be an Eb,
降 3 是 Eb ，
the flatted fifth would be a Gb,
降 5 是 Gb ，
flatted seventh would be a Bb.
降 7 是 Bb 。
Okay, remember we can use our minor pentatonic form
好的，记得我们可以用小调五声音阶形式
to cover almost all of our Blues notes
来覆盖几乎所有的布鲁斯音符
and the [], in the chord progressions that we need to cover
在和弦进程中，我们需要覆盖的，
by using that minor pentatonic,
通过使用小调五声音阶，
so if I want to sound bluesy,
所以如果我想听起来很布鲁斯，
let's say you're playing Blues in C,
我们假设你在弹奏 C 中的布鲁斯，
I just start playing my C minor pentatonic
我弹奏我的 C 小调五声音阶，
and that's when it starts paying off for me.
这就是它开始给我带来回报的时候。
Okay, let's go through that minor pentatonic form,
好的，让我们来看看这个小调五声音阶形式，
we're going to start in A, A minor pentatonic,
我们从 A 小调五声音阶开始，
we're going to go through the different forms adding those Blues notes.
我们将通过不同的形式添加那些布鲁斯音符。
Okay, so here we are in the first position adding the Blues notes,
好的，所以我们在第一个位置添加布鲁斯音符，
ready go,
准备，开始，
let's go down,
我们往下，
let's do it one more time,
让我们再来一次，
ready, play.
准备，弹奏。
So let's say I wanted to play an F Blues,
假设我想弹奏 F 布鲁斯，
okay, so song comes up, it's an F
好的，所以歌曲是 F 调，
and I want to sound bluesy,
我想听起来布鲁斯，
I go down to my F minor pentatonic
我到 F 小调五声音阶，
and I can derive notes out of that scale,
我可以从那个音阶得到音符，
let's practice that scale one time in F,
让我们在 F 中练习那个音阶，
slowly and then we'll do it faster,
缓慢地，然后我们会做得更快，
so you can get it underneath your fingers,
这样你可以掌握它，
ready, go,
准备，开始，
okay, a little bit faster,
好的，快一点，
ready, go.
准备，开始。
Great, now [] at Bb,
好的，现在到 Bb ，
ready, go
准备，开始，
great, now let's do it in E,
好的，现在我们到 E ，
well, I can't go low, I start running out of notes,
我不能再低了，我的音符开始用完了，
so I gotta go high,
所以我得更高，
ready, go.
准备，开始。
Great, now remember what a Blues chord progression is,
好的，记得布鲁斯进程是什么吗，
four bars of one, two bars of four,
四小节 1 ，两小节 4 ，
back to one for two bars, five, four, and then one for two bars.
两小节 1 ， 5 4 ，两小节 1 。
Okay, so if we're playing in C,
好的，如果我们在 C 中弹奏，
it would be like this,
它就会是这样，
now let's play,
现在我们来弹奏，
I'm going to turn the loop on again
我将再次打开循环，
and let's play a C, let's just do a C7,
我们来弹奏 C ，我们来做 C7 ，
okay, going to an F7, G7,
到 F7 ， G7 ，
we'll just add seven to all these major chords,
把 7 加到所有大和弦上，
for this purposes right now,
为了现在的目的，
so let's do the example in C,
所以让我们用 C 来做这个例子，
F7,
F7 ，
C,
C ，
G7,
G7 ，
let's switch some different forms around,
让我们换一些不同的形式，
two C7 here,
两个 C7 ，
F7,
F7 ，
C7,
C7 ，
G7,
G7 ，
F7,
F7 ，
C7.
C7 。
Great, now we're gonna do it in E,
好的，现在我们要在 E 中弹奏，
and we're going to practice the Blues progression in E,
我们将在 E 中练习布鲁斯进程，
you ready,
你准备好了吗，
let's go,
我们开始，
then A7,
然后 A7 ，
you don't always have to have the same rhythm,
你不必总是有相同的节奏，
try and find a different form to play.
尝试找到不同的弹奏形式。
Okay, this time we're going to the E Blues
好的，这一次我们要弹奏 E 布鲁斯，
and I want you to solo using that minor pentatonic form,
我想让你使用那个小调五声音阶形式 solo ，
over this E chord progression,
通过这个 E 和弦进程，
I'll play the chords,
我将弹奏和弦，
but you go ahead and try and solo over the top of it.
但你继续，试着使用它 solo 。
Okay, let's try it,
好的，让我们试一试，
just use that E minor pentatonic form,
使用 E 小调五声音阶形式，
through those blues if you want to.
通过那些布鲁斯。
Now you gotta remember,
现在你要记住，
when you're doing scales and you're trying soloing,
当你在做音阶和尝试 solo 的时候，
the main thing about soloing is making music,
solo 的主要内容是做音乐，
not just going through your scales,
不仅是通过你的音阶，
it doesn't sound very much like music,
它听起来并不太像音乐，
when you're just going,
当你只是，
that doesn't make very good music,
这没有很好的音乐，
you need to take parts of those,
你需要把它们的一部分，
those are just kind of the colors that you're using,
那些只是你在使用的音色，
those are the building blocks that you're building a solo out of,
那些是你构建独奏的基础，
so try not thinking of it, try not think of it so linearly,
所以试着不要这么线性地想它，
don't think of it as a scale,
不要把它想成一个标尺，
think of it as you're just grabbing these pieces
把它想象成你只是抓住这些碎片，
and trying to make something out of it.
并试图从中创造出一些东西。
Okay, we're gonna play one more time,
好的，我们再弹一次，
I'm going to play a phrase
我先弹一段，
and then you're going to play a phrase
然后你们再弹一段，
to see if you can play what I played right after me,
看看你能不能弹我后面弹的，
let's try it.
让我们试一试。
Now you play,
现在你弹，
let's do another one.
让我们再弹一个。
Great, soloing is all about getting your creative ideas
好的， solo 就是得到你有创意的点子，
and being able to make something musical out of them,
并用它们创造出一些音乐的东西，
I encourage you to keep trying,
我鼓励你继续尝试，
keep experimenting with those Jam tracks
继续试验那些 Jam 曲目，
and the different chord progressions that we have laid out for you,
以及我们为你安排的不同的和弦进程，
the more practice you get with them,
你用它们练习得越多，
the better your ear is going to be,
你的耳朵就会更好，
at hearing the things that you want to play
听到你想演奏的东西，
and be able to translate them through your fingers,
并能够通过你的手指翻译它们，
we'll see you next time.
我们下次再见。